<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HashiCorp on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/tags/hashicorp/</link><description>Recent content in HashiCorp on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.greenreedtech.com/tags/hashicorp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HashiCorp Vault Unique AppRole Identity Logging</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-unique-approle-identity-logging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-unique-approle-identity-logging/</guid><description>HashiCorp Vault supports several authentication methods for human and non-human access. Several of the non-human authentication methods are tied to specific platforms or clouds such as AWS, Kubernetes, Azure, and others. For workloads that are running on non-supported platforms, the AppRole authentication method is typically recommended for authentication. The AppRole method uses a role as the core construct as the name implies.</description></item><item><title>HashiCorp Vault vSphere Authentication with VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA)</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-vsphere-authentication-with-vmware-event-broker-appliance-veba/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-vsphere-authentication-with-vmware-event-broker-appliance-veba/</guid><description>HashiCorp Vault supports a number of authentication methods including methods that utilize what HashiCorp refers to as a &amp;ldquo;trusted platform&amp;rdquo;. These include public clouds such as AWS, Azure and GCP along with platforms like Kubernetes. This method of authentication simplifies the introduction of the initial credential or secret that a workload must present to Vault by making use of information about itself that it already knows.</description></item><item><title>Identifying Active HashiCorp Vault Root Tokens</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/identifying-active-hashicorp-vault-root-tokens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/identifying-active-hashicorp-vault-root-tokens/</guid><description>Revoking the root token on a production HashiCorp Vault deployment is one of the recommended best practices for securing an instance of HashiCorp Vault. The actual process to revoke the root token is fairly straightforward by running the vault token revoke command and providing the root token at the command line.</description></item><item><title>HashiCorp Packer Puppet Bolt Provisioner</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-packer-puppet-bolt-provisioner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-packer-puppet-bolt-provisioner/</guid><description>Treating workloads as &amp;ldquo;cattle&amp;rdquo; or immutable is a popular management paradigm for stateless workloads and is especially prevalent for such workloads that are hosted in a public cloud. The concept is based upon the notion that servers are pre-baked with all of the software that is needed for the application and any stateful data is pushed to an external persistent storage mechanism such as an object storage or a message queue.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Puppet Provisioner</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/terraform-puppet-provisioner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/terraform-puppet-provisioner/</guid><description>HashiCorp Terraform 0.12.2 added official support for a Puppet provisioner. One caveat is that the provisioner is only available in 0.12.x of Terraform. The provisioner provides a number of features such as adding data to the CSR for trusted facts, selecting between open source and enterprise agent versions along with autosigning the CSR.</description></item><item><title>HashiCorp Vault Policy Metrics</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-policy-metrics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-policy-metrics/</guid><description>I gave a talk for HashiCorp&amp;rsquo;s HashiDays event earlier this year that centered around operational intelligence for HashiCorp Vault. The focus was on harnessing data and turning it into actionable insight to help drive informed decisions. One common insight that&amp;rsquo;s often required but not natively available for various reasons is a mechanism to identify what identities a policy is assigned to within Vault.</description></item><item><title>Vault Audit Logging</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vault-audit-logging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vault-audit-logging/</guid><description>Vault (https://www.vaultproject.io/) is a secrets management tool created by HashiCorp that is extremely popular. Given the sensitive nature of the data being stored by a Vault server it is critical that auditing be configured appropriately to provide a record of who accessed sensitive data and when it was accessed. In this blog post we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through configuring a Vault server for auditing and dump the log entries to an AWS S3 bucket for centralized storage.</description></item></channel></rss>