<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HashiCorp Vault Unique AppRole Identity Logging</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/hashicorp-vault-unique-approle-identity-logging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/hashicorp-vault-unique-approle-identity-logging/</guid><description>HashiCorp Vault supports several authentication methods for human and non-human access. Several of the non-human authentication methods are tied to specific platforms or clouds such as AWS, Kubernetes, Azure, and others. For workloads that are running on non-supported platforms, the AppRole authentication method is typically recommended for authentication. The AppRole method uses a role as the core construct as the name implies.</description></item><item><title>HashiCorp Vault vSphere Authentication with VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA)</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/hashicorp-vault-vsphere-authentication-with-vmware-event-broker-appliance-veba/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/hashicorp-vault-vsphere-authentication-with-vmware-event-broker-appliance-veba/</guid><description>HashiCorp Vault supports a number of authentication methods including methods that utilize what HashiCorp refers to as a &amp;ldquo;trusted platform&amp;rdquo;. These include public clouds such as AWS, Azure and GCP along with platforms like Kubernetes. This method of authentication simplifies the introduction of the initial credential or secret that a workload must present to Vault by making use of information about itself that it already knows.</description></item></channel></rss>