<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrating Gitness with Jenkins</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/integrating-gitness-with-jenkins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/integrating-gitness-with-jenkins/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jenkins is a popular open source CI server and many that are familiar with it often have a bit of a love/hate relationship. That being said, it is an incredibly powerful and flexible tool that is often used when there&amp;rsquo;s a need for a platform for building CI/CD pipelines to deploy code or infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Gitness</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/getting-started-with-gitness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/getting-started-with-gitness/</guid><description>&lt;p>With everything being defined as code nowadays, there&amp;rsquo;s a need for a place to store and version that code. The popular selection would be a version control system (VCS) and more specifically, a git server. There&amp;rsquo;s a myriad of options that include hosted solutions such as Github, Azure DevOps, GitLab.com as well as self-hosted solutions such as Gogs, Gitea, and Gitlab. At this point I&amp;rsquo;ve used all of the aformentioned solutions but given that I do most of my tinkering in my homelab, I was looking for a self-hosted solution. A primary requirement was a simple and lightweight solution without all of the bells and whistles as I mainly needed it for just source control. I had heard about Harness introducing a VCS solution (&lt;a href="https://gitness.com/">gitness&lt;/a>) sometime ago but hadn&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to kicking the tires.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Argo Workflows</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/getting-started-with-argo-workflows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/getting-started-with-argo-workflows/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the technologies that I find the most enjoyable working with are orchestration solutions that are used to stitch together complex processes. Over my career I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with solutions like VMware vRealize Orchestrator (vRO), StackStorm, as well as countless CI/CD platforms that are commonly used to orchestrate various processes. In this blog post we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at a solution that I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to try out for quite some time in Argo Workflows. This is part of the broader umbrella of projects that includes ArgoCD, the popular GitOps solution for Kubernetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Puppet Bolt Terraform Inventory Plugin</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/puppet-bolt-terraform-inventory-plugin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/puppet-bolt-terraform-inventory-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>HashiCorp Terraform is a popular Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool that is used for provisioning virtual machines or cloud instances along with other resources. Once a virtual machine or cloud instance is provisioned typically it still needs to be configured which includes security baselines, application dependency configuration and even application deployment. The tasks are generally accomplished with a Configuration Management (CM) tool such as Puppet or Puppet Bolt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NetApp: Highly Performant Storage for Cloud Native Apps</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/netapp-highly-performant-storage-for-cloud-native-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/netapp-highly-performant-storage-for-cloud-native-apps/</guid><description>&lt;p>NetApp was one of the &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;legacy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> companies that presented a number of compelling solutions at &lt;a href="http://techfieldday.com/event/cfd3/">Cloud Field Day #3&lt;/a>. The challenge for many similar companies is how do you continue to stay relevant given the pace at which technology moves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kubernetes is the defacto container orchestration platform created by Google that is one of the hottest technologies within the IT industry at this time. One of the still developing areas with containers is the management of stateful applications which for many is an anti-pattern for containers which they feel should be stateless. The challenge with stateful applications running in containers is that there must be some sort of persistent storage to allow the state to survive the destruction of the container. This is where a company like NetApp comes into the picture.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Useful Docker Commands</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/useful-docker-commands/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/useful-docker-commands/</guid><description>&lt;p>Docker (&lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/">https://www.docker.com/&lt;/a>) is arguably the most popular container platform and this post covers a number of useful Docker commands from basic commands about viewing system information to viewing logs of docker containers. Additional commands can be found at the Docker docs website (&lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/cli/">https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/cli/&lt;/a>) or via the command line help.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="docker-version">Docker Version&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>View the version of docker installed on the system. Both the client and server version are listed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jenkins Job Builder</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/jenkins-job-builder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/jenkins-job-builder/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently a co-worker of mine (Thanks Ken Erwin) introduced me to Jenkins Job Builder (&lt;a href="http://docs.openstack.org/infra/jenkins-job-builder/">http://docs.openstack.org/infra/jenkins-job-builder/&lt;/a>) which is a project created by the OpenStack infrastructure team that aims to automate the creation of Jenkins Jobs. The software is written in python and utilizes either yaml or json files as the framework for creating Jenkins jobs. A list of some of the primary features is provided below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jenkins Active Directory</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/jenkins-active-directory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/jenkins-active-directory/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post covers integrating Jenkins CI server with Microsoft Active Directory to provide centralized authentication.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="step-1---install-he-active-directory-plugin">Step #1 - Install he Active Directory plugin&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Click &amp;ldquo;Manage Jenkins&amp;rdquo; from the sidebar&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com/greenreedtech.com/jce_folders/Jenkins_AD_1.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Click &amp;ldquo;Manage Plugins&amp;rdquo; to install the Active Directory plugin&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com/greenreedtech.com/jce_folders/Jenkins_AD_2.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Click on the &amp;ldquo;Available&amp;rdquo; tab, enter &amp;ldquo;Active Directory&amp;rdquo; in the &amp;ldquo;Filter:&amp;rdquo; search box, click the checkbox next to &amp;ldquo;Active Directory plugin&amp;rdquo; and finally click &amp;ldquo;Download now and install after restart&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>