<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/vmware/</link><description>Recent content in VMware on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware NSX+ Overview - Tech Field Day Extra</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vmware-nsx-overview-tech-field-day-extra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vmware-nsx-overview-tech-field-day-extra/</guid><description>VMware recently presented at the Tech Field Day Extra event during VMware Explore 2023. The presentation covered VMware&amp;rsquo;s networking and security product updates.
Cross-Cloud Vision VMware has been building out a cross-cloud solution that enables enterprise organizations to seamlessly deploy workloads to &amp;ldquo;any&amp;rdquo; cloud. This is being realized by building out operating environments in hyperscaler clouds such as AWS (VMC on AWS), Azure, GCP (Google Cloud VMware Engine), IBM Cloud (IBM Cloud for VMware Solutions), Oracle Cloud (Oracle Cloud VMware Solutions), and others.</description></item><item><title>Building a Lightweight Container Host for VMware vSphere</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/building-a-lightweight-container-host-for-vmware-vsphere/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/building-a-lightweight-container-host-for-vmware-vsphere/</guid><description>Containerization and Kubernetes have dominated the IT conversation for the last handful of years. Containers enable rapid development, application portability and a myriad of other benefits. Containers rely on a host operating system in order to run and ideally it would be one that is extremely lightweight since the apps running in the containers are what we really care about.</description></item><item><title>VMware vSphere VM iPXE Boot without DHCP</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vmware-vsphere-vm-ipxe-boot-without-dhcp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vmware-vsphere-vm-ipxe-boot-without-dhcp/</guid><description>Network booting operating systems isn’t a new concept and has been around for years. Bare metal deployments are typically where network booting is commonly used. Most network cards are equipped with a network boot rom that enables the server to boot from the network using the PXE protocol. The PXE protocol is an old protocol that offers limited functionality.</description></item><item><title>Creating a VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) Golang Function</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/creating-a-vmware-event-broker-appliance-veba-golang-function/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/creating-a-vmware-event-broker-appliance-veba-golang-function/</guid><description>The VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) fling is a really interesting project that enables administrators to take advantage of event driven automation in a VMware vSphere environment. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to kick the tires on using the appliance as I&amp;rsquo;ve thought a lot about vSphere event driven security and what that looks like from a technical implementation perspective.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) and PostgreSQL Database SSL</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-orchestrator-vro-and-postgresql-database-ssl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-orchestrator-vro-and-postgresql-database-ssl/</guid><description>In a previous post we walked through configuring a PostgreSQL database server as the external database for our vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) cluster. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll cover adding SSL support to encrypt the traffic between our vReazlie Orchestrator cluster and our PostgreSQL database server.
PostgreSQL SSL Configuration Generate CSR The first thing we need to do is get our SSL certificate for the database server.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) Cluster with a PostgreSQL Database</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-orchestrator-vro-cluster-with-a-postgresql-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-orchestrator-vro-cluster-with-a-postgresql-database/</guid><description>In this post we&amp;rsquo;re going to build out a two node vRealize Orchestrator cluster with a PostgreSQL database. VMware is deprecating support for Microsoft SQL and Oracle databases as the vRO external database in favor of PostgreSQL.
https://docs.vmware.com/en/vRealize-Orchestrator/7.3/rn/vrealize-orchestrator-73-release-notes.html
PostgreSQL database installation and configuration The first thing we need to do is install and configure PostgreSQL on a linux server.</description></item><item><title>vRA 7.2 dynamic property list from REST API</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vra-7.2-dynamic-property-list-from-rest-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vra-7.2-dynamic-property-list-from-rest-api/</guid><description>In this post we&amp;rsquo;re going to walk through how to dynamically populate a vRA request field using values retrieved from a REST API using vRO.
A common scenario when working with any software is wanting to test against multiple versions of the software.
In this example we&amp;rsquo;re going to dynamically fetch the software version of StackStorm (https://stackstorm.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.2 hardening compliance with vRO and Splunk</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-automation-7.2-hardening-compliance-with-vro-and-splunk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-automation-7.2-hardening-compliance-with-vro-and-splunk/</guid><description>In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how we can utilize vRealize Orchestrator and Splunk to determine how compliant our vRA appliance is with the vRealize Automation 7.2 hardening guide.
vRA 7.2 hardening compliance script The first task is utilizing a script to check the settings specified in the hardening guide. In our case we&amp;rsquo;re going to generate JSON output from the script in order to easily ingest the data into Splunk.</description></item><item><title>vRO - Building a dynamic drop-down for vSphere tags</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vro-building-a-dynamic-drop-down-for-vsphere-tags/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vro-building-a-dynamic-drop-down-for-vsphere-tags/</guid><description>A recent blog post by Rob Nelson about using vRO to provision VMs with vSphere tags (https://rnelson0.com/2017/04/06/vrealize-orchestrator-workflows-for-puppet-enterprise/) got me thinking about how to present a dynamic list of vSphere tags in vRO. So in this post we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how to create a dynamic drop-down list of vSphere tags in vRO.</description></item><item><title>vRA7 Chatops with StackStorm</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vra7-chatops-with-stackstorm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vra7-chatops-with-stackstorm/</guid><description>ChatOps is a pretty cool and still emerging technology that allows users to initiate actions on external systems from within a messaging platform such as slack. There are already bots available from vendors such as opvizor (http://www.opvizor.com/opbot/) that provide this functionality in a productized solution. In the case of opvizor, their bot interacts with VMware vSphere.</description></item><item><title>Puppet Policy Based Autosigning with vRA7</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/puppet-policy-based-autosigning-with-vra7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/puppet-policy-based-autosigning-with-vra7/</guid><description>What is Policy Based Autosigning A critical aspect of any Puppet deployment is determining how we want to allow nodes to get their certificate signed by the Puppet master. Before we delve into policy based autosigning we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the other three methods for managing certificate signing.
Manual
Manually signing certs breaks automated deployment processes.</description></item></channel></rss>