<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vRO on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</title>
    <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/vro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vRO on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/vro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) and PostgreSQL Database SSL</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-orchestrator-vro-and-postgresql-database-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-orchestrator-vro-and-postgresql-database-ssl/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post we walked through configuring a PostgreSQL database server as the external database for our vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) cluster. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll cover adding SSL support to encrypt the traffic between our vReazlie Orchestrator cluster and our PostgreSQL database server.
PostgreSQL SSL Configuration Generate CSR The first thing we need to do is get our SSL certificate for the database server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) Cluster with a PostgreSQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-orchestrator-vro-cluster-with-a-postgresql-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vrealize-orchestrator-vro-cluster-with-a-postgresql-database/</guid>
      <description>In this post we&amp;rsquo;re going to build out a two node vRealize Orchestrator cluster with a PostgreSQL database. VMware is deprecating support for Microsoft SQL and Oracle databases as the vRO external database in favor of PostgreSQL.
https://docs.vmware.com/en/vRealize-Orchestrator/7.3/rn/vrealize-orchestrator-73-release-notes.html
PostgreSQL database installation and configuration The first thing we need to do is install and configure PostgreSQL on a linux server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRO - Building a dynamic drop-down for vSphere tags</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vro-building-a-dynamic-drop-down-for-vsphere-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vro-building-a-dynamic-drop-down-for-vsphere-tags/</guid>
      <description>A recent blog post by Rob Nelson about using vRO to provision VMs with vSphere tags (https://rnelson0.com/2017/04/06/vrealize-orchestrator-workflows-for-puppet-enterprise/) got me thinking about how to present a dynamic list of vSphere tags in vRO. So in this post we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how to create a dynamic drop-down list of vSphere tags in vRO.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
