<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Career on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/categories/career/</link><description>Recent content in Career on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/categories/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving to Morpheus Data</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/moving-to-morpheus-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/moving-to-morpheus-data/</guid><description>I have made the decision to become the director of technical marketing at Morpheus Data and I start that new position today. Morpheus Data is a company that I became aware of during Cloud Field Day 3 (CFD3) while serving as a delegate for the event. Cloud Field Day is one of several events hosted by Gestalt IT in which several vendors present one at a time to a group of IT professionals that ask questions and provide feedback about the presentations.</description></item><item><title>Detecting HashiCorp Vault Root Token Generation</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/detecting-hashicorp-vault-root-token-generation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/detecting-hashicorp-vault-root-token-generation/</guid><description>HashiCorp Vault generates a default root token during installation and best practice dictates that the token should be revoked once the deployment has been setup. There are certain critical operations that can only be carried out by a root token and requires that a new root token be generated. Given the immense power that the root token garners it would be ideal to identify when a root token is generated.</description></item><item><title>Detecting HashiCorp Vault Root Login</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/detecting-hashicorp-vault-root-login/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/detecting-hashicorp-vault-root-login/</guid><description>Security of a HashiCorp Vault deployment is of paramount importance given the sensitive nature of the information contained within the platform. During the initial configuration process the root token is used to perform the setup and should be used to create less privileged named accounts. These accounts should be used for day to day administration of the Vault deployment and the root token should only be used in scenarios where it is absolutely necessary.</description></item><item><title>Puppet Bolt Vault Inventory Plugin</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/puppet-bolt-vault-inventory-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/puppet-bolt-vault-inventory-plugin/</guid><description>In this blog post we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the HashiCorp Vault plugin for Puppet Bolt that enables authentication credentials for Bolt to be retrieved from an instance of HashiCorp Vault. HashiCorp Vault is a secrets management platform that is commonly used to store secrets such as API keys, passwords and SSH private keys.</description></item><item><title>The Next Chapter at Puppet</title><link>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/the-next-chapter-at-puppet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martezr.github.io/greenreedtech-website/the-next-chapter-at-puppet/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m now in my second week at Puppet which is best known for its configuration management software that shares the same name as the company. I&amp;rsquo;m extremely excited about this new chapter in my professional life and this blog post covers some of the reasons why. Hopefully this will provide anyone reading this with helpful information as they come to an inflection point in their career.</description></item></channel></rss>