<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vault on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</title>
    <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/vault/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vault on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/vault/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Detecting HashiCorp Vault Policy Changes</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/detecting-hashicorp-vault-policy-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/detecting-hashicorp-vault-policy-changes/</guid>
      <description>Security of a HashiCorp Vault deployment is of paramount importance given the sensitive nature of the information contained within the platform. Policies within the platform are used to grant and deny access to the sensitive information stored in the platform.
All operations in HashiCorp Vault are audited and can be shipped to a centralized logging server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp Vault Unique AppRole Identity Logging</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-unique-approle-identity-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-unique-approle-identity-logging/</guid>
      <description>HashiCorp Vault supports several authentication methods for human and non-human access. Several of the non-human authentication methods are tied to specific platforms or clouds such as AWS, Kubernetes, Azure, and others. For workloads that are running on non-supported platforms, the AppRole authentication method is typically recommended for authentication. The AppRole method uses a role as the core construct as the name implies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Active HashiCorp Vault Root Tokens</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/identifying-active-hashicorp-vault-root-tokens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/identifying-active-hashicorp-vault-root-tokens/</guid>
      <description>Revoking the root token on a production HashiCorp Vault deployment is one of the recommended best practices for securing an instance of HashiCorp Vault. The actual process to revoke the root token is fairly straightforward by running the vault token revoke command and providing the root token at the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting HashiCorp Vault Root Token Generation</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/detecting-hashicorp-vault-root-token-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/detecting-hashicorp-vault-root-token-generation/</guid>
      <description>HashiCorp Vault generates a default root token during installation and best practice dictates that the token should be revoked once the deployment has been setup. There are certain critical operations that can only be carried out by a root token and requires that a new root token be generated. Given the immense power that the root token garners it would be ideal to identify when a root token is generated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting HashiCorp Vault Root Login</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/detecting-hashicorp-vault-root-login/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/detecting-hashicorp-vault-root-login/</guid>
      <description>Security of a HashiCorp Vault deployment is of paramount importance given the sensitive nature of the information contained within the platform. During the initial configuration process the root token is used to perform the setup and should be used to create less privileged named accounts. These accounts should be used for day to day administration of the Vault deployment and the root token should only be used in scenarios where it is absolutely necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp Vault Policy Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-policy-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/hashicorp-vault-policy-metrics/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk for HashiCorp&amp;rsquo;s HashiDays event earlier this year that centered around operational intelligence for HashiCorp Vault. The focus was on harnessing data and turning it into actionable insight to help drive informed decisions. One common insight that&amp;rsquo;s often required but not natively available for various reasons is a mechanism to identify what identities a policy is assigned to within Vault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vault Hardening Compliance using Chef InSpec</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vault-hardening-compliance-using-chef-inspec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vault-hardening-compliance-using-chef-inspec/</guid>
      <description>HashiCorp Vault is quickly becoming the defacto secrets management platform used in environments that rely on DevOps concepts for application delivery. Vault is incredibly easy and simple to get started with but takes a bit of thought and planning to operationalize it.
One of the challenges is ensuring that the installation of your security platform is secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vault Audit Logging</title>
      <link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vault-audit-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vault-audit-logging/</guid>
      <description>Vault (https://www.vaultproject.io/) is a secrets management tool created by HashiCorp that is extremely popular. Given the sensitive nature of the data being stored by a Vault server it is critical that auditing be configured appropriately to provide a record of who accessed sensitive data and when it was accessed. In this blog post we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through configuring a Vault server for auditing and dump the log entries to an AWS S3 bucket for centralized storage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
