<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>StackStorm on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/stackstorm/</link><description>Recent content in StackStorm on Green Reed Technology - Technology without boundaries</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.greenreedtech.com/categories/stackstorm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deployment Pipeline Chaos Engineering with StackStorm and ChaosToolkit</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/deployment-pipeline-chaos-engineering-with-stackstorm-and-chaostoolkit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/deployment-pipeline-chaos-engineering-with-stackstorm-and-chaostoolkit/</guid><description>Chaos Engineering is the practice of experimenting or injecting faults into a system to test how the system responds to the failure (https://principlesofchaos.org). Chaos Engineering is still new for many organizations and can be a daunting practice to adopt at first but even baby steps into the practice can be immediately beneficial.</description></item><item><title>Advanced VMware vSphere Template Orchestration</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/advanced-vmware-vsphere-template-orchestration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/advanced-vmware-vsphere-template-orchestration/</guid><description>Template management is a critical facet of infrastructure management and traditionally one of the more challenging operations there is. The advent of tools like HashiCorp Packer have provided administrators with the ability declaratively automate the template creation process.
Automation is great but in most organizations a single piece of automation is part of a larger process that includes tickets and potentially other hand offs.</description></item><item><title>vRA7 Chatops with StackStorm</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vra7-chatops-with-stackstorm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vra7-chatops-with-stackstorm/</guid><description>ChatOps is a pretty cool and still emerging technology that allows users to initiate actions on external systems from within a messaging platform such as slack. There are already bots available from vendors such as opvizor (http://www.opvizor.com/opbot/) that provide this functionality in a productized solution. In the case of opvizor, their bot interacts with VMware vSphere.</description></item><item><title>vSphere Alarms with Slack and StackStorm</title><link>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vsphere-alarms-with-slack-and-stackstorm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.greenreedtech.com/vsphere-alarms-with-slack-and-stackstorm/</guid><description>Being notified of when something happens in your environment has always been important and has evolved over time from basic emails to IM messages via tools like Slack.
This post will cover posting alarm information to Slack via StackStorm. In addition post alarm information to Slack we can take autoremediation actions in response to alarms which we&amp;rsquo;ll cover in later posts.</description></item></channel></rss>